A Guide to the Clifton Community Woman’s Club Collection, 1971-2014
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Clifton Community Woman’s Club Collection, 1971-2014
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-48
7.0 linear feet
The Clifton Community Woman’s Club Collection consists of 7.0 linear feet and spans the years 1971-2014. The collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, treasurer’s reports, newsletters, and club scrapbooks.
Clifton Community Woman’s Club
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Clifton Community Woman’s Club in September 2009 (Judy Anderson), February 2013 (Patricia A. Riedinger), and July 2016
Historical and Biographical Information
The Clifton Community Woman’s Club (CCWC) was formed in November 1970 and federated by the General Federation of Women’s Clubs (GFWC) in the spring of 1971. The founding of the club was driven by an interest in preserving the quality of life and historical value of the Clifton area, formed by a group of woman who met during efforts to prevent the construction of a landfill, an airfield, and an outdoor amphitheater in the area. The CCWC holds monthly meetings as well as social and educational events throughout the year for its members. The club provides charitable contributions to a number of organizations, funds several scholarships, and has completed a number of community improvement programs over the years. The club’s signature fundraising event is the Clifton Homes Tour, which they began in 1972 and is held every spring. The club also participates in the annual Clifton Day and has hosted a monthly Senior Citizens’ Luncheon for local residents since 1974. A major project of the club’s was dismantling, moving, and rebuilding the old Fairfax Station. The rebuilt station was dedicated in 1987 and in 1988 became the Fairfax Station Railroad Museum, founded by CCWC member Lena Wyckoff. Between 1973 and 1990, the club had a choral group, called the Holly Singers, that performed at various club and private functions.
Scope and Content
The Clifton Community Woman’s Club Collection consists of 7.0 linear feet and spans the years 1971-2014. The collection contains correspondence, meeting minutes, treasurer’s reports, newsletters, and club scrapbooks. Subjects include the history and events of the Clifton Community Woman’s Club, Clifton Homes Tour, and Fairfax Station Railroad Museum.
Series 1: Administrative Papers, 1972-2009, Box 1
This series contains by-laws of the club, guidelines for taking meeting minutes, miscellaneous correspondence, and a summary of the club’s history.
Series 2: Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 1970-2014, Box 1
This series includes minutes of monthly meetings of the club and of the Executive Board. Beginning in May 1979, meeting minutes are included for both the Day Unit and the Night Unit of the CCWC. (The club began the Night Division, later called the Night Unit, in 1979 to accommodate members who could not attend weekday morning meetings.) Beginning in 2009, treasurer’s reports are included as attachments to club and board meeting minutes. Also included are two years of separate treasurer’s reports.
Series 3: Newsletters, 1971-2014, Box 2
This series includes monthly newsletters produced by the club, which include a President’s message, meeting and event calendars, articles and notices on topics of interest, and summaries of club events, charitable activities, and programs.
Series 4: Scrapbooks, 1971-2002, Boxes 3-6
This series includes 19 scrapbooks containing photographs from club events, programs from club events, newspaper clippings related to the club or its members, and certificates of merit and appreciation, many awarded by the Virginia Federation of Women’s Clubs. One scrapbook (labeled “Earth, Sea, Sky”) documents the club’s capital improvement program in 1974 to obtain historic landmark designation for the town of Clifton and several buildings and sites. One scrapbook (labeled “Holly Singers”) includes photos and programs from performances and activities of the club’s choral group, the Holly Singers.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Clifton (Va.) - History; Clifton Community Woman’s Club (Clifton, Va.); Clifton Homes Tour (Clifton, Va.); Fairfax Station Railroad Museum (Fairfax, Va.)
Container List
- Series 1: Administrative Papers, 1972-2009
  - By-laws, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Guidelines for Taking Meeting Minutes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1972, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Club History, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 1970-2014
  - Meeting Minutes, 1970 November-1972 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1972 April-1973 March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1973 April-1973 October (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1973 November-1974 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1974 April-1974 August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1974 September-1975 March (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1975 April-1976 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1976 April-1977 March (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1977 April-1978 March (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1978 April-1979 March (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1979 April-1980 March (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1980 April-1981 March (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1981 April-1982 March (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1982 April-1983 March (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1983 April-1984 February (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1984 March-1985 February (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1985 March-1986 February (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1986 March-1987 February (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1987 March-1988 June (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1988 August-1989 February (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1989 March-1990 February (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1990 March-1991 February (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1991 March-1992 February (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1992 March-1993 February (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1993 March-1994 February (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1994 March-1995 February (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1995 March-1996 February (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1996 March-1997 February (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1997 March-1998 February (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1998 March-1999 February (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1999 March-2000 February (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2000 March-2001 February (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2001 March-2002 February (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2002 March-2003 February (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2003 March-2004 February (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2004 March-2005 February (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2005 March-2005 June (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2007 August-2008 June (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2008 August-2009 June (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 2009 August-2009 December (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 2010 January-2010 June (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 2010 September-2011 June (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 2011 August-2012 August (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 2012 September-2013 May (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Meeting Minutes and Treasurer’s Reports, 2013 August-2014 June (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Treasurers Reports, 1973 March-1975 March (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Series 3: Newsletters, 1971-2014
  - Newsletters, 1971 January-1972 January (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1972 February-1973 March (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1973 April-1974 March (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1974 April-1975 March (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1975 April-1976 March (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1976 April-1977 March (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1977 April-1978 March (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 1978 April-1979 March (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 1979 April-1980 February (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 1980 March-1981 March (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 1981 March-1982 February (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1982 March-1983 March (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, 1983 April-1984 March (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, 1984 April-1985 March (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters, 1985 April-1986 February (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, 1986 April-1987 March (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, 1987 April-1988 March (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, 1988 April-1989 March (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, 1989 April-1990 March (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, 1990 April-1991 March (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, 1991 April-1992 March (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, 1992 April-1992 June (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters, 1994 June-1995 March (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters, 1995 April-1996 June (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters, 1996 September-1997 June (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters, 1997 September-1998 June (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Newsletters, 1998 September-1999 June (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Newsletters, 1999 September-1999 December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters, 2009 September-2010 April (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Newsletters, 2010 May-2011 January (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Newsletters, 2011 February-2011 May (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newsletters, 2013 September-2014 June (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Series 4: Scrapbooks, 1971-2002
  - Scrapbook, 1971-1972, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1972, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1972, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1972-1976, 1978-1980, 1972-1980 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1973, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1973, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, Earth, Sea, Sky, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1974-1975, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1974-1976, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, Holly Singers, 1976-1991 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1981-1984, 1981-1984 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1984, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1985-1986, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1986-1992, 1986-1992 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1993-1996, 1993-1996 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1994-1996, 1994-1996 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1997-1998, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1998-2001, 1998-2001 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 2001-2002, 2001-2002 (Box 5)